[Music]
welcome back to the channel we are back
from which microsoft shop yes we are
back from our holidays
i've eaten way too much ice cream we've
done some reviews just to keep the
channel ticking over while we were there
but now today we are gonna get right
back into it and make a ben and jerry's
flavor we're gonna do coffee coffee buzz
buzz buzz as you know i love my coffee
so this might be a nice one for me to
make
let's get stuck into it and see how it's
done
[Music]
so the first thing we're going to do is
make our espresso fudge and for that
we're going to take a whole can of
condensed milk it's also called
sweetened condensed milk although there
are identical things
put that in a pan
gently get that warmed up adding in your
chocolate once the chocolate is
completely melted into your condensed
milk then add in your instant espresso
powder make sure that's nicely combined
give it a quick stir to try and get
those espresso flavors mixed throughout
then put it in a lined container in the
fridge for a few hours to harden at that
point you can divide it up into
individual servings if you wish
now onto the ice cream base itself we've
used this technique before and it's a
really really good one so we're going to
take our milk and put it on the hob and
warm it gently now we're going to add in
our ground coffee beans you can use
instant coffee you can use whole coffee
beans if you like whole coffee beans
takes a bit longer because the surface
area of the coffee beans is much smaller
compared to the ground beans but the
overall flavor at the end and strength
will be the same
leave this warmed milk and coffee mix on
the hob ticking over for at least an
hour
at that point take your milk put it back
in the pan and add in your sugars your
egg yolks and your skim milk powder
i've added 0.2
stabilizer to the sugars before adding
them in you don't have to do that if you
don't want to
once that's all nicely combined take it
off the heat put it in a container add
in your cream brings the temperature
down nice and quickly and then put it in
a fridge for a few hours to completely
chill once the base is completely
chilled you can take it out and put it
in your ice cream machine to let it
churn
whilst the ice cream is churning take
out a serving of your chocolate espresso
fudge now this is straight out the
freezer so it's quite difficult to chop
but it's the ideal way and time to do it
otherwise this can get really sticky and
really messy chop it up into whatever
size pieces you like i've tried to stay
something like half centimeter squares
here but
however is absolutely fine
put it in a little container to the side
and just before your ice cream is
completely churned to your liking add in
your espresso fudge pieces let it all
combine and then put it in your tub put
that in the freezer for at least four
hours
[Music]
and here we go
look we haven't done a tub my wife and i
was saying that we haven't had a tub for
a while
and as it's just coffee coffee buzz buzz
buzz buzz buzz buzz obviously is bees
let's take this lovely fun little tub
and get some ice cream dished up
[Music]
so
scoops lovely smells really strong
it's one of those things coffee ice
cream
obviously it depends on the type of
coffee you have in canada their instant
coffee was shockingly bad
i mean to be fair the ground coffee
wasn't great either
tim horton's coffee is just
i'm not even going to describe that i'd
be three hours away the best there was
starbucks and i'm not a big fan of that
either
so
you know it's all subjective everyone
likes different coffee
use whatever you like
flavor-wise to make your coffee ice
cream if you like
nescafe gold blend instant use that if
you like a specific type of bean use
that if you like a one brand of
pre-ground coffee
use that the result is going to be
perfect because it's to your taste
here we go
now
i've used
a ground version of
this this is
from a roaster here in
england
we've got a couple of their different
beans and pre-ground it's great coffee
really really nice flavor
we've used this before in the past the
sakura pre-ground that's a really nice
soft flavored coffee
and we also have this which i drink
generally on a day-to-day basis is the
azira
normal nest cafe
i'm not a big fan of but that's that's
surprisingly good so just use whatever
suits you
let's see
what this tastes like first
[Music]
that's good
that is really good
texture spot on zero iciness in there
super smooth
strong coffee flavor
and that's something that
one of the
the ice creameries or scoop shops
whatever you want to call it that we
went to whilst we were away had a coffee
ice cream there it was so bad i threw it
in the bin
it tasted burnt
it didn't taste like coffee it just
tasted disgusting
it was considering it was made in a
batch freezer and not a home machine
although our machine is probably the
most professional home machine you can
get
it was awful so
some people can get this really quite
wrong um
one thing i want to mention about ben
jerry's coffee coffee buzz buzz buzz is
something that someone mentioned in one
of the reviews
and that is on their website it said
that they messaged
this person and called themselves kkk
that they were curious about the
caffeine content because they're quite
sensitive to it so they reached out to
the customer service
and ben and joe's came back to them and
said that our coffee coffee buzz by the
buzz has 46.5 milligrams of caffeine per
100 gram
serving
now that might sound like
a lot
but in reality
i found a website that goes through all
the different caffeine contents of your
everyday kind of coffees obviously this
is going to be very specific depending
on where you live
but over here uh one mug
which is generally considered anywhere
from 250 to 300 milliliters
one mug of instant coffee is a hundred
milligrams caffeine and one mug of
filter coffee is 140 milligrams of
caffeine so your filter coffee will
still stand for your
whole beans
as well as something like your your
pre-ground that will be the same give or
take caffeine content
obviously espresso has
by and large more caffeine in it but
it's such a small serving that you
actually get much less per drink
so if if you really want a
strong coffee flavor and you want to use
instant you're going to have to use a
fair bit more
instant coffee
i'd say probably per liter somewhere
around 8 to 10 teaspoons of instant
coffee will give you the same strength
coffee ice cream that pre-ground or
beans
for steeping for an hour obviously for
beans i would recommend you steep it
much longer maybe even overnight just to
get that strength of flavor through
again that's the surface area of the
bean is much lower than the pre-ground
so it's quicker to get the flavor out of
pre-ground than it is for whole beans
the flavor is the same it's the same
product it's the same bean
so if you like a coffee bean
grind it
soak it
warm milk good to go
the espresso fudge i've used this fudge
before
it's good it's really easy to make off
the shelf condensed milk whatever
chocolate you like i mean i probably
would stick with a dark chocolate
something 56 and over again you know to
get the espresso flavor
into the fudge
on the back of the banana joe's tub it
says
coffee
flavor
what that is
your guess is as good as mine likely a
coffee extract but
if you can't get a good instant coffee
then by all means use coffee extract
something like that its flavor is not
quite the same but
it'll do the job
you've got a really nice
texture change with the coffee fudge in
there it's just a wave of caffeine in
this so
if you're sensitive to caffeine like
that reviewer on ben and joe's website
was
maybe just you know tone it down a
little bit if you're not like me and you
need as much as you can get to get you
through the day
go for your life this is gonna really
wake you up some so
anyway thanks very much for watching uh
now that we're back here we're going to
continue with our making ice cream
videos actually i've managed to get hold
of the last two sunday flavors the vegan
one
and the hazelnut one so we'll do a
review video for those we managed to
gain our first troll on our last video
so yeah it means we're doing something
right
don't forget to like and subscribe
and we'll see you next time
you